Finding Aid for Frederick A. Coller reprints of articles on medical subjects, 1924-1955
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frederick A. Coller reprints of articles on medical subjects, 1924-1955 1924-1955
Coller, Frederick A.
7216 DA 2; C697; R425
Professor of surgery in the University of Michigan Medical School. Reprints of articles
1 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collections was assembled from various sources.
No further additions to the records expected.
The collection is open to research.
Frederick A. Coller was professor of surgery in the University of Michigan Medical School.
This is a collection of reprints of the writings of Frederick A. Coller gathered from different sources.
Subjects:
Coller, Frederick A.; Medicine.; Surgery.
- Pamphlets (Box 1)
  - Abdominal Disease-Simulating Coronary Occlusion. (The American Journal of the Medical Sciences, August, 1934 )
  - Abdominal Incisions. (Tribute to Lloyd Noland, 1947 )
  - Acute Obstruction of the Small Bowel. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, May 14, 1949 )
  - Address of the President; The State of the Association. (Annals of Surgery, September, 1944 )
  - The Administration of Fluid to the Sick Patient. (Maine Medical Journal, August, 1937 )
  - Anatomic and Clinical Study of the Transverse Abdominal Incision. (Archives of Surgery, August, 1943 )
  - Anterior Sacral Meningocele. (Surgery, Gynecology and Obstetrics, June, 1943 )
  - Appendico-Vesical Fistula. (The American Journal of Surgery, September, 1934 )
  - Blood Loss in Surgical Operations. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, September, 1944 )
  - Cancer of the Colon. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, December, 1947 )
  - Cancer of the Colon and Rectum: Concepts of Treatment. (University of Michigan Medical Bulletin, November, 1955 )
  - Cancer of the Rectum. (Annals of Surgery, June, 1952 )
  - Carcinoma of the Rectum. (Surgery, Gynecology and Obstetrics, March, 1944 )
  - Carcinoma of the Stomach: Observations on Surgical Treatment. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, February, 1932 )
  - Chromaffin Cell Tumor Causing Paroxysmal Hypertension, Relieved by Operation. (Archives of Surgery, June, 1934 )
  - Chronic Biliary Typhoid Carriers. (Surgery,, St. Louis, September, 1942 )
  - Clinical And Experimental Observations on Parathyroid Transplants. (Transactions of the American Association for the Study of Goiter,, 1937 )
  - Correction of Blood Loss During Surgical Operations. (Surgery, Gynecology and Obstetrics, April, 1946 )
  - A Critical Evaluation of Lumbar Sympathectomy for Peripheral Arteriosclerotic Vascular Disease. (Surgery,, St. Louis, January, 1955 )
  - Dehydration. (Surgery, Gynecology, and Obstetrics, August, 1936 )
  - Dehydration Attendant on Surgical Operations. (The Journal of the American Medical Association September, 1932 )
  - The Development of the Technique of Thyroidectomy. (Surgery, Gynecology and Obstetrics, October, 1937 )
  - The Diagnosis and Treatment of Breast Tumors. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, April, 1948 )
  - The Differentiation of Spastic from Organic Periferal Vascular Occlusion by the Skin-Temperature Response to High Environmental Temperature. (Annals of Surgery, October, 1932 )
  - The Early Results of Sympathectomy in Far-advanced Arteriosclerotic Peripheral Vascular Disease. (Surgery,, St. Louis, July, 1949 )
  - The End-results of Thyroidectomy. (Annals of Surgery, October, 1931 )
  - Endemic Goiter, a Precancerous Lesion. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, August, 1925 )
  - Evaluation of the Palliative Operation for Cancer of the Pancreas, (The American Journal of Surgery, July, 1934 )
  - The Fascial Spaces of the Neck in Acute Infection. (The American Journal of Surgery, December, 1939 )
  - The Follow-up Study of Patients with Thromboangiitis Obliterans (Buerger's Disease). (Surgery, St. Louis December, 1949 )
  - The Function of Periferal Vasoconstriction, (Annals of Surgery, November, 1934 )
  - Gas Gangrene in Civil Surgery. (The Military Surgeon, July, 1937 )
  - Immunization of the Peritoneum. (The American Journal of Surgery, October, 1939 )
  - Indications for Splenectomy. (Surgery, St. Louis May, 1955
  - The Inevitable Damage Consequent Upon Goiter. (The Boston Medical and Surgical Journal, September, 1925 )
  - Intestinal Fistula. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, September, 1934 )
  - Lesions of the Extremities Associated With Diabetes Mellitus. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, July, 1925 )
  - Maintenance of Normal Water Exchange with Intravenous Fluids. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, November, 1936 )
  - The Management of the Jaundiced Patient, with Special Reference to Vitamin K. (Surgery, Gynecology and Obstetrics, July, 1941 )
  - Max Minor Peet, 1885-1949. (Transactions of the American Surgical Association,, 1949 )
  - A Method of Draping for Operations on the Neck. (The American Journal of Surgery, January, 1930 )
  - The Morbidity of Endemic Goiter. (American Medical Association, May, 1924 )
  - Multiple Polyposis of the Colon; a Preliminary Report. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, September, 1955 )
  - The Neuroendocrine Control of Water and Electrolyte Excretion during Surgical Anesthesia. (Surgery, Gynecology and Obstetrics, August, 1952 )
  - Observations on Acute Appendicitis: Factors Influencing Mortality. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, May, 1931 )
  - The One Stage Procedure of the Treatment of Carcinoma of the Rectum. (Annals of Surgery, October, 1936 )
  - Peripheral Vasoconstruction by Tobacco and its Relation to Thrombo-Angiitis Obliterans. (Annals of Surgery, July, 1933 )
  - Peripheral Vaso-constriction by Tobacco Demonstrated by Skin Temperature Changes. (Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine,, 1932 )
  - Peritonitis. (Proceedings of the Inter-State Post-graduate Medical Assembly of North America, October, 1941 )
  - Physiological Principles of Pre-and Post-operative Care of Surgical Patients. (The Mississippi Doctor, February, 1937 )
  - Pituitary Basophilism (Cushing's Syndrome): Report of a Verified Case, with a Discussion of the Differential Diagnosis and Treatment. (Archives of Internal Medicine, August, 1936 )
  - Postoperative Complications. (Proceedings of the Interstate Postgraduate Medical Assembly of North America, October, 1940 )
  - Postoperative Complications. (The Southern Surgeon, August, 1942 )
  - Postoperative Salt Intolerance. (Annals of Surgery, April, 1944 )
  - Preoperative and Postoperative Care. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, November, 1949 )
  - Shock and Collapse. Acidosis and Alkalosis. Water Balance. 2 versions including revised editions. (Preoperative and Postoperative Care,, 1934 ? )
  - Present Policies in the Treatment of the Severely Burned Patient: an Outline of Treatment Including the Use of Whole Blood Transfusions. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, May, 1946 )
  - The Quantitative Determination of Water Losses in Surgical Patients. (The Southern Medical Journal, March, 1934 )
  - Quantitative Studies of the Replacement of Body Chlorides. (Proceedings of The Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine,, 1938 )
  - Reactions of the Peritoneum to Trauma and Infection. (Archives of Surgery, November, 1939 )
  - Regional Lymphatic Metasteses of Carcinoma of the Colon. (Annals of Surgery, July, 1941 )
  - Regional Lymphatic Metastasis of Carcinoma of the Rectum. (Surgery,, St. Louis, August, 1940 )
  - Regional Lymphatic Metastases of Carcinoma of the Stomach. (Archives of Surgery, November, 1941 )
  - The Relation of the Spread of Infection to Fascial Planes in the Neck and Thorax. (Surgery,, St. Louis, March, 1937 )
  - The Replacement of Sodium Chloride in Surgical Patients. (Annals of Surgery, October, 1938 )
  - Response to Parenteral Glucose of Normal Kidneys and of Kidneys of Postoperative Patients. (Annals of Surgery, January, 1949 )
  - A Review of Studies on Water and Electrolyte Balance in Surgical Patients. (Surgery,, St. Louis, August, 1942 )
  - Richard Root Smith, 1869-1940. (Bulletin, American College of Surgeons, June, 1940 )
  - Riedels Struma, (The Western Journal of Surgery, Obstetrics & Gynecology, October, 1935 )
  - The Role of the Extremities in the Dissipation of Heat. (The American Journal of Physiology, December, 1933 )
  - Role of the Transverse Abdominal Incision and Early Ambulation in the Reduction of Postoperative Complications. (Archives of Surgery, December, 1949 )
  - Scrutiny of Progress Against Cancer. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, April, 1955 )
  - Serum Sodium in Relation to Liver Damage and Hyperthroidism. (Proceedings of The Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine,, 1937 )
  - La Simpatectomia Lumbar, (La Revista de la Policlinica Caracus, Mayo-Junio, 1947 )
  - Sodium Chloride Content of Gastro-Intestinal Secretions. (Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine,, 1937 )
  - Some Important Factors of Postoperative Treatment. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, April, 1933 )
  - Some Surgical Aspects of Disease of the Gall Bladder. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, January, 1936 )
  - The Spleen and Some of its Diseases that May be Treated by Surgery. (Annals of the Royal College of Surgeons of England, December, 1955 )
  - Studies in Water Balance, Dehydration and the Administration of Parenteral Fluids. (Minnesota Medicine, August, 1936 )
  - Studies in Water Requirements of Surgical Patients. (Anesthesia and Analgesia,, Melbourne Australia May-June, 1935 )
  - Studies of the Blood Chemistry in Thyroid Crisis. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, December, 1937 )
  - Studies on the Reaction of the Peritoneum to Trauma and Infection. (Annals of Surgery, June, 1939 )
  - A Study of the Interrelationships of Salt Solutions Serum and Defibrinated Blood in the Treatment of Severely Scalded, Anesthetized Dogs. (Annals of Surgery, September, 1944 )
  - The Surgery of Modern Warfare. (Surgery, Gynecology, and Obstetrics, January, 1941 )
  - Surgical Aspects of Hypoglycemia Associated with Damage to the Liver. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, January, 1939 )
  - Surgical Decompression in Biliary Obstruction. (Annals of Surgery, January, 1952 )
  - The Surgical Treatment of Chronic Biliary Typhoid Carriers. (Annals of Surgery, May, 1937 )
  - Surgical Treatment of Long-Standing Deep Phlebitis of the Leg. (Surgery, St. Louis, May, 1944 )
  - Tetanus: A Review of Eighty-one Cases. (University of Michigan Medical Bulletin, August, 1952 )
  - Tetra-Ethyl-Ammonium as an Adjunct in the Treatment of Peripheral Vascular Disease and other Painful States. (Annals of Surgery, June, 1947 )
  - Thrombo-Angiitis Obliterans and Tobacco. (The American Heart Journal, July, 1936 )
  - Thrombo-Embolism. (Surgery,, St. Louis, February, 1945 )
  - Thyroid Crisis: Its Relation to Liver Function and Adrenalin. (Western Journal of Surgery, Obstetrics and Gynecology, September, 1936 )
  - Thyroidectomy for Goiter Without Hyperthyroidism: Post operative results from Adenomatous Goiters with Normal and Hypofunction. (The Western Journal of Surgery, Obstetrics and Gynecology, July, 1931 )
  - Total Gastrectomy: Effects upon Nutrition and Hematopoieses. (Surgery,, St. Louis, June, 1943 )
  - Translocation of Fluid Produced by the Intravenous Administration of Isotonic Salt Solutions in Man Postoperatively. (Annals of Surgery, October, 1945 )
  - Treatment of Carcinoma of the Colon. (Annals of Surgery, April, 1945 )
  - The Treatment of Peritonitis Associated With Appendicitis. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, December, 1934 )
  - The Treatment of Peritonitis Associated with Appendicitis. (The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society, November, 1933 )
  - The Treatment of Renal Insufficiency in the Surgical Patient. (Annals of Surgery, September, 1948 )
  - Urinary Retention Following the Combined Abdomino-Perineal Resection for Rectal Carcinoma. (University Hospital Bulletin,, Univ. of Michigan, September, 1942 )
  - Urinary Retention Following the Combined Abdominoperineal Resection. (Surgery,, St. Louis, August, 1943 )
  - The Use of Hypotonic Solutions in the Postoperative Treatment of Surgical Patients. (University Hospital Bulletin,, University of Michigan, August, 1945 )
  - The Use of Parrafin as a Primary Dressing for Skin Grafts. (Surgery, Gynecology and Obstetrics, August, 1925 )
  - The Use of Sulfanilamide in the Peritoneum: Experimental and Clinical Observations. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, January, 1942 )
  - The Use of Testosterone in Preventing Postoperative Liver Dysfunction in the Poor Risk Surgical Patient. (Annals of Surgery, October, 1952 )
  - Water and Electrolyte Balance. (Surgery, Gynecology and Obstetrics, February, 1940 )
  - Water and Electrolytes [no publisher, no date]
  - Water Balance in Patients With Hyperthyroidism. (Western Journal of Surgery, Obstetrics & Gynecology, August, 1933 )
  - Water Balance in Surgery. (The Journal of the American Medical Association, January, 1937 )
  - Water Balance in Surgery Patients. (Surgery, Gynecology & Obstetrics, July, 1934 )
  - Water Balance in Surgical Conditions. (International Clinics,, Vol. III, Series 44, 1934 )
  - Water Balance in Surgical Patients. (The Nebraska State Medical Journal, October, 1935 )
  - Water Balance of Sick Patients. (Wisconsin Medical Journal, August, 1936 )
  - The Water Requirements of Surgical Patients. (Annals of Surgery, November, 1933 )
  - Water Metabolism. (The Journal of the Indiana State Medical Association, April, 1937 )
  - Wounds of Warfare. (The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, January, 1943 )